<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-01-07T22:09:34-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Colin Williams’ Writing</title><entry><title type="html">The Strike</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/01/07/the-strike.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Strike" /><published>2019-01-07T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-01-07T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/01/07/the-strike</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/01/07/the-strike.html">&lt;p&gt;The sun beats down as Grue pulls him arm back, preparing to
strike. Beads of sweat form on his brow from the exertion, mingling
with his beard as it runs down his face.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His stance is solid, the right foot behind with the toe pointed out at
an angle. His left foot is forward, leading his body in the assault.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The warhammar in his hand seems almost like an extension of his arm,
giving credit to the traditions of his people. It reaches one extreme
and he begins to swing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His posture shifts forward, toes digging into the grass and dirt. The
goblin in front of him cowers as he sees his fate clearly. Eyes
darting from side to side, looking for any opportunity to escape.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a pathetic attempt to soften the blow, the goblin raises its hands
up, so it’s the first thing the warhammar connects with. The power of
the strike cares little of their presence, and barely even slows on
its journey downward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, the warhammar connects, instantly dispatching Grue’s foe. Its
job done, Grue wipes the hammer clean and straps it to his back, ready
for the next time it’s needed.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The sun beats down as Grue pulls him arm back, preparing to strike. Beads of sweat form on his brow from the exertion, mingling with his beard as it runs down his face.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">We Go Spelunking</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/01/07/we-go-spelunking.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="We Go Spelunking" /><published>2019-01-07T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-01-07T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/01/07/we-go-spelunking</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/01/07/we-go-spelunking.html">&lt;p&gt;Despite his inability to carry on a reasonable conversation, Grue
bluffed his way out of the keep without implicating his
companions. Upon rejoining them, the party inadvertently revealed to
the guards that the drawbridge to the city was down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Somewhat concerned, they sent someone to raise the bridge, and
our adventurers curiously followed. As the bridge was being raised,
Kella’s companions charged across, being pursued by a horde of orcs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Initial contact with this new group proves rocky, but then what do you
expect from a Dwarven Hermit and a Half-Orc Barbarian? Undaunted, when
Cade arrives he gives it another try and they immediately take to him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, the rest of the party is extremely concerned about the
Orcs. Grue is also convinced this Human party is more than just
hapless victims, a suspicion bolstered by Cade’s discovery that
they’re in the “Real Estate” business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unbeknownst to our heroes, a few of the Orcs forded the river and
engaged in combat with the suspicious band of travelers. Not
particularly interested in the outcome of this fight, our heroes
“persuade” the guard to lower the drawbridge enough that they can leap
across the river on their horses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cade and Luukha escape successfully, but Gruebound and Malxiris
weren’t so lucky. Although the two of them were blurred, the horse was
perfectly visible, and that’s where one of the Orcs aimed. Flung to
the ground, the mob descended on the two of them, beating them to
within an inch of their lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If it weren’t for the elves suddenly appearing from the forest, they
surely would have perished. Fortunately, distracted by this new foe,
they barely noticed Cade and Luukha return to assist in the party’s
escape.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Retreating towards the caves, the adventurers make camp to lick their
wounds. After a good nights rest, everybody was in much better spirits, and
they set out to investigate the caves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Loudly entering through the front entrance, they quickly draw the
attention of an Ogre, Nob, and several Goblins. Undaunted by its size,
Grue approaches and begins proselytizing about The Arrangement. To his
credit, Nob is enthralled, and remains so until Cade sneaks around and
attacks from behind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Malxiris uses her connection to magic to put two of the Goblins to
sleep. While the rest of the party kept the waking foes busy, she took
measures to ensure they would never wake again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luukha was the front line, tough enough to go toe to toe with Nob, as
well as a second Ogre named Thog who was awoken by the racket. While
defeating such powerful foes was certainly a team effort, she dealt
the finishing blows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After recovering from their fight, they set out to explore the
cave. The first couple of tunnels proved uninteresting, although their
inability to decipher the bubbling goo in one cavern probably belied
this observation. Grue carefully obtains a mushroom near that goo to
examine later, but the area seemed largely uninteresting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the third cavern, though, they discovered the villagers that had
been imprisoned by the Goblins. Their egress was hindered by a swarm
of bats that attacked upon any noise. The adventurers heroically led
the villagers to safety, suffering only a few minor cuts and scrapes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the safety of the outdoors, they broke the news of Lady Nandar’s
death to them. Morak Ur’Grey, the Innkeeper, realizes the Bard he
hired ended up being his savior, and we learn that a few commoners had
been herded deeper into the cave.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Despite his inability to carry on a reasonable conversation, Grue bluffed his way out of the keep without implicating his companions. Upon rejoining them, the party inadvertently revealed to the guards that the drawbridge to the city was down.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Gruebound Ironarm’s Backstory</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/01/06/gruebound-ironarms-backstory.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Gruebound Ironarm's Backstory" /><published>2019-01-06T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-01-06T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/01/06/gruebound-ironarms-backstory</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/01/06/gruebound-ironarms-backstory.html">&lt;p&gt;The first light of the day illuminates a figure slumped over a
scroll. Gruebound Ironfist wakes with a start and realizes he’s done
it again. Falling asleep in the library isn’t an offense on its own,
but missing Prime is. The service to Pelor is already in full swing
when he arrives, and Grue slips in the back hoping nobody will notice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the close, Elbrin Ironfist turns and walks straight towards
him. “So, I noticed you slipping in late today. You show such promise,
Grue, but you can’t neglect your obligations as a Cleric.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yes, Elbrin.” Grue says obediently, falling into step behind him as
he sweeps past. Grue owes much to his mentor, he can’t even imagine
where he’d be today without him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“So what was so important you had to miss Prime?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I found a strange arrangement of rocks in the library, and I was
attempting to place their origin.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Elbrin stops so suddenly Grue runs into him. “Improving your mind I
could almost understand, but staring at a bunch of stones is a
monumental waste of your time.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“But some of them were lighting up, and it almost seemed as if someone
was trying to communicate with me.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Triumvant College is an open-minded place, but even academics have
their limits. You were probably so tired you didn’t even realize you
were casting Light cantrips on them. Take my advice and put them out
of your mind, you could do great things if you kept focused on your
studies.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Grue did try to put it out of his mind, he truly did. He couldn’t
bring himself to cast the stones aside, but they were piled in the
corner of his room for months. The problem was that, every once in a
while he would catch them lighting up in patterns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One night, he finally caved and spread them out on the floor. After
staring at them for what could have been hours, but just as likely to
be scarce minutes, a pattern started to emerge. Excited, he gathered
them up and brought them to Elbrin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I knew it! They’re trying to say something to me!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He spread the stones out on the ground, and Elbrin looked down at them
with an exasperated expression. He composed himself and said “OK,
Grue, show me and maybe I’ll believe you.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They sat and watched them all night. Grue in anxious anticipation,
Elbrin calm veneered over just a hint of fury. As dawn breaks without
so much of a glimmer from the stones, Elbrin reaches over and pats him
on the leg.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Look at it this way, now we can finally put this unpleasant obsession
behind us. Why don’t you take a break, spend some time in the mines,
nothing helps a dwarf think clearly like the feel of chisel against
rock. I’ll speak to the other instructors, given your standing I’m
sure they’d understand the need for a few weeks away from the books.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Grue appreciated his compassion, the mine definitely sounded
appealing. Perhaps, if he saw stones light up there, he’d finally
convince himself it was his own cantrips. He almost did, too, he would
repeatedly notice glints of light out of the corner of his eye, only
to discover they were precious stones catching the light.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Upon returning to Triumvant, he was horrified to discover that the
arrangement were no longer in his room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He blustered into Elbrin’s offce, “They’re gone! What did you do with
them?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Relax, Grue, it was for your own good. They won’t bother you ever
again.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’ll find them, something was trying to communicate with me and
you’re not going to stop them!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“No, you won’t. I scattered them across the nearby rocky beach, you’ll
never be able to find those precise stones again.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I will, and you know what else? I’m no longer an Ironfist.” Gruebound
Ironarm walked out of his office, the college and left his life behind
them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Descending to the beach, he realized the daunting task ahead of
him. Stretched as far as the eye could see were stones, all about the
right size and shape to be part of The Arrangement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He was meticulous, examining each stone carefully before moving to the
next. Some would glow, some would stay dark, in the end he had a bag
about the same size as the one he found in the library. The keen
intelligence he was once known for broken, all that matters now is The
Arrangement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Years later, Grue sits on the floor of his cave, meditating with the
stones spread around him. He knows he’s forgotten something, but try
as he might his memory eludes him…&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The first light of the day illuminates a figure slumped over a scroll. Gruebound Ironfist wakes with a start and realizes he’s done it again. Falling asleep in the library isn’t an offense on its own, but missing Prime is. The service to Pelor is already in full swing when he arrives, and Grue slips in the back hoping nobody will notice.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Malxiris Gaalxoturros’ Backstory</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/01/06/malxiris-gaalxoturros-backstory.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Malxiris Gaalxoturros' Backstory" /><published>2019-01-06T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-01-06T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/01/06/malxiris-gaalxoturros-backstory</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/01/06/malxiris-gaalxoturros-backstory.html">&lt;p&gt;The monastery is all Malxiris has ever really known. Her clutch was
unusually large, and a way to gain prestige is for a family to give
one of its eggs to the cloister. One of her favorite parts of the
monastery is the library, housing one of the largest collections of
arcane lore in the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Knowledge is everything in her community, scholars could learn so much
from them, if only they could get past their prejudice and fear of
dragonborn. They are tirelessly reaching out into the community,
helping the needy, welcoming all to study in their library. It’s
strange, though, smiling and offering their guests dinner always seems
to drive them away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One guest that stayed, though, was Gruebound Ironfist. He was such a
clean, brilliant, scholar, Malxiris can scarcely believe the wretched
pile of filth she sees now is the same person. One thing certainly is
the same, though, he’s always been interested in everything around
him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Her favorite time of year is when most people in the monastery return
to the nest for Pip Day. It’s a point of pride to her that her first
crack was the second largest in her clutch, and the only one to have a
piece of egg flake off in the process. The whole community gathers to
see the new dragonborn pip, and the imprecise nature of the event
brings them together for a full week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One day, when studying in the library, she came across a faded
scroll. It had an odd texture, almost what Malxiris imagined human
skin would feel like, and contained several darkly themed
illuminations, along with all of the “i”s dotted with ornate green
eyes. That night, and every night since, that same eye has appeared in
her dreams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With time, she learned Cyäegha was reaching out to her, inviting her
to form a pact. Her desire to learn more about this partnership is
what ultimately motivated her to leave the monastery. As ardent
supporters of knowledge, she had their full support, and the letters
she sends back accounting her experiences become part of the library.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once a month, Malxiris feels compelled to climb to the top of the
tallest hill and perform a ritual she doesn’t really understand…&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The monastery is all Malxiris has ever really known. Her clutch was unusually large, and a way to gain prestige is for a family to give one of its eggs to the cloister. One of her favorite parts of the monastery is the library, housing one of the largest collections of arcane lore in the world.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Getting Home</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/01/04/getting-home.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Getting Home" /><published>2019-01-04T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-01-04T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/01/04/getting-home</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/01/04/getting-home.html">&lt;p&gt;It has been so long since I’ve seen my house. My memory of it is
faded, but I focus and remember a spell memorized years before. The
techniques I learned prior to Shadow have served me well, and the
spell I had been holding in my head for so long is still strong and
clear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A glow rings my head, establishing a connection to the Blue Sun and
revealing the thread I must follow. The path is long and dangerous,
but that journey pales compared to the prospect of homelessness. It
twists and winds its way around my head, eventually leading to the
desired memory caged within the tendrils of a Memory Kraken.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could pull it away, burn it into oblivion, that is within my power.
Maybe the stick isn’t a good choice, though, perhaps the carrot would
be more effective; I gather mundane memories I can offer to gain its
trust.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hold in my hand fragments of little importance: tying my shoes,
brushing my teeth, anything routine or mundane. Pulling them apart and
spreading them around the filthy tendrils causes them to loosen their
grip, its hunger temporarily sated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What memory should I offer in its place? Everything seems so precious,
then it hits me: I can trick it into feeding on itself. Of all the
thoughts in my head, the one I’m creating right now is singularly
unique.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I coax the beast toward that morsel, and it reaches out eagerly. This
is a crucial point, I must move on before its grip tightens and traps
me as well. I see a large opening, realize there are mere seconds
until it is enveloped, and I dive through…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m sorry, what were we talking about? I really don’t have time to
chat, you see I’ve only just remembered where I live and I’d very much
like to get home.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">It has been so long since I’ve seen my house. My memory of it is faded, but I focus and remember a spell memorized years before. The techniques I learned prior to Shadow have served me well, and the spell I had been holding in my head for so long is still strong and clear.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">In the beginning…</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/12/28/in-the-beginning.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="In the beginning..." /><published>2018-12-28T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-12-28T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018/12/28/in-the-beginning</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/12/28/in-the-beginning.html">&lt;p&gt;It was a cool and crisp day when four adventurers met by chance at an
intersection in a glen outside Waterdeep. In the distance chimed bells
sounding much like a distress call, and Luukha convinced this unlikely
group to investigate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The party finds the town of Nightstone largely abandoned by its
inhabitants, and the large stone which served as a centerpiece was
mysteriously missing. Strewn about are several boulders, seeming to
have caused a significant amount of damage to some of the buildings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By a temple to Milekki they encountered some Wargs, and inside they
encounter some difficulty. After cutting the rope pulling the bell,
the weight crashes through nearly flattening Cade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Afterwards, in the stable, Malxiris is ambushed by a goblin. In her
surprise she unleashes her formidable breath and sets the building
aflame. Fortunately, with the assistance of Luukha and Gruebound, they
were able to rescue the horses tied up inside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cade, on the other hand, is having none of these shenanigans and
instead visits the nearby Inn. He learns from a monk named Kella that
the villagers had been taken to a nearby cave by goblins, and the
scattered boulders seemed almost as if they had been dropped.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point, our adventurers chose to split up. Malxiris and Luukha
explored some of the houses, while Cade and Gruebound visited the
graveyard. Malxiris tamed a Tressom at Xelbrin’s, which she named
Hanoos. They also visited the homes of Aganor and Somerhawk, but found
very little of note. Grue was very interested opening the crypt, but
lacked the tools to accomplish his goal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While Grue struggled fruitlessly against the sealed crypt, Cade joined
Malxiris and Luukha in looting the general store. The goblin inside
was quickly dispatched, and by the time Grue joined them the action
had ended. Luukha begrudgingly shared her crowbar with him, and
ultimately assisted in pointlessly defiling the Nandar crypt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having explored the town, they chose to visit the nearby Keep before
investigating the cave where the villagers were held. The guards
fortified within were charmed by the party, sharing that the boulders
came from Sky Castle. Gruebound’s curiosity and lack of tact proved
problematic, though, and after being assaulted by a magical sword he
causes enough noise to draw the attention of two guards. He disguises
himself as one of them, but chose a face that is unrecognizable to
them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How will he escape? Will the villagers be rescued from the goblins?
What is Sky Castle and why is it dropping rocks on Nightstone?&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">It was a cool and crisp day when four adventurers met by chance at an intersection in a glen outside Waterdeep. In the distance chimed bells sounding much like a distress call, and Luukha convinced this unlikely group to investigate.</summary></entry></feed>